

## **PROFILE**

Cloud DevOps Engineer with 2 years 5 months of experience in AWS and DevOps environment, tools and techniques i.e., CI/CD and Agile Methodologies. Quick learning ability to enhance with new technologies with a good aptitude and logical approach.

## **OBJECTIVE**

To work on a challenging environment in a progressive organization that would leverage my learning and experience to the fullest potential and align my growth with the growth of the organization.

## CONTACT

PHONE:

91-9583163896

LOCATION:

Bangalore, India

**EMAIL:** 

sarthipatha2064@gmail.com

## **HOBBIES**

Cookina Travelling Gardening Painting

# PARTHA NANDA

**Cloud DevOps Engineer** 

# **EDUCATION**

Graduation - [B. Tech - 7.22 CGPA] 2012 - 2016

Intermediate - [CHSE - 65.66%] 2010 - 2012

Matriculation - [ICSE - 80.14%] 2009 - 2010

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Amazon Development Centre India Pvt Ltd.

Jr. Cloud DevOps Engineer

[2020 - 2022] 2+ years

Experience in GIT, Jenkins, Docker, AWS, Linux, Sim, JIRA.

## Amazon Development Centre India Pvt Ltd.

**Analyst** 

[2018 - 2020] 1.5+ years

Monitoring & reporting of schedule deviations and managing SL.

Amazon Development Centre India Pvt Ltd.

Sr. Associate

[2016 - 2018] 1.5+ years

Acted as a Technical Account Manager for selling Partners.

#### **TOOLS USED**

• Version Control System:

• Build Tool:

Maven

**GIT** 

• Continuous Integration Tool: • Web Server:

**Jenkins Nginx** 

• Containerization Tool:

Docker

• Ticketing Tool:

JIRA, SIM **AWS** 

• Cloud Technology: • Operating System:

Linux, Windows

# **WORK EXPERIENCE (PROJECT)**

E-commerce online shopping Application: Amazon Seller Service Line/Areas: End to End Infrastructure Development

Business Title: Jr. Cloud DevOps Engineer

- Good understanding of Cloud Computing. Responsible to create Virtual Private Clouds to deploy resources.
- Involved in creation of multiple resources like EC2 / ELB / EBS volumes / S3 / RDS from the AWS cloud.
- Created Multiple Firewalls (Security groups (inbound / outbound rules)) to avoid / block unwanted traffic and connection with subnet level security via NACL's configurations.
- Configured the multiple subnets and route connectivity.
- Configured the Connectivity of Resources between multiple VPC via VPC peering.
- Created Routes / IP Table to secure resources like EC2 / RDS / ELB / EBS instances.
- Configured CIDR range for multiple VPC's and subnets.
- Understand Performance and basic Security for Infrastructure.
- Involved into the planning and taking a decision to choose a CI and CD for our application.
- Source code management using GitHub to support continuous development and integration.
- Performed Branching, Merging, tagging activities using GitHub.
- Developed and maintained automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment using Jenkins.
- Modified and implemented Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment pipeline.
- Monitored and fixed the builds running in Jenkins.
- Worked on Docker for build and deployment. Created Docker images, containers, volumes.
- Used Docker to create Docker Images and stored in Docker trusted registry.
- Supported different environments like Dev and Testing.
- Worked with developers and testers to clarify build details and resolve any conflicts and maintained a standard automated build process and raised tickets using ticketing tool Sim and JIRA.
- Coordinated with different teams and Project Managers to achieve required project timelines.

Web-based Application: Seller Central

Service Line/Areas: Real Time Monitoring using internal tools (Quicksight and CCM)

Business Title: Analyst

- Monitoring & reporting of schedule deviations like breaks, absenteeism, late login, early logout and other schedule non-adherence.
- Managing Service Level (SL) for both In-house and partner sites. Coordinate with partner sites on SL management over 24x7 bridge.
- Work on real-time tickets related to non-production activities.
- Recognize and initiate escalation process for system outages and submit tickets to the hot desk as per SOP to ensure service levels are maintained.
- Serves as primary interface between WFM and Site Operation leadership to strengthen partnership.
- Hands on experience on using AWS tools like Quicksight, Chime, AWS Connect.
- Ability to meet deadlines and prioritize tasks

Web-based Application: Paragon

Service Line/Areas: Provides prompt and efficient service to Amazon Sellers and Merchants

Business Title: Sr. Associate

- Verifying and auditing compliance documents such as GMP, COA, FSSAI License, Test reports, invoices etc. of Sellers
- Ungating Sellers to sell restricted products on Amazon platform.
- Helped in filling the SOP gap in Amazon and have worked on more than 10 internal tools.
- Assisted new hires and provided support whenever required.
- Awarded Best Performer 2 times in a Row and has been recognized for maintaining 100% on Quality.
- Addressing any grievance issues of sellers with regard to their business with Amazon.
- Providing approval to sellers to sell on Amazon and clearing Seller's concern regarding payments and processed various types of reimbursements to the Sellers.